Faraaz Pathan

Senior Software Engineer

Innovative Software Engineer offering 4 years of experience in .NET Technology . Seasoned professional with background in full software development lifecycle. Quickly learns and masters new technologies while working in both team and self-directed settings.

faraazofficial3@gmail.com

Ahmedabad

in linkedin.com/in/FaraazPathan

9725183556

faraazpathan.github.io/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Cygnet Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Cygnet GSP

10/2018 - Present Solution to automate GST Returns filing.

Sr. Software Engineer.

Role

- Designed, Developed and Maintained GST returns like GSTR1, ITC04 for number of clients.
- Developed Modules to import excel files, Authentication and Authorization using traditional way as well as Azure AD, LDAP and Azure/OKTA SAML.
- Technologies Used: ASP.Net standard/core, SQL Server, Dapper, Rabbit MQ, JS, Jquery, Html and CSS.

Cygnet Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

SeraBrynn's Carver

03/2018 - 09/2018 Software Engineer.

Solution to Automate Cyber Security Audit and gap analysis.

Role.

- Designed, Developed and Maintained Application's Dashboard and Admin module.
- Technologies Used: ASP.Net Core, SQL Server, Entity Framework, JS, Jquery, Html and CSS.

Cygnet Infotech Pvt. Ltd. Idox's Icarus and Gatwick

idox s icai as alia dacwic

Associate Software Engineer

A real time solution for tracking and managing bus activities in Cities and Airport (Gatwick London).

Role.

- Developed and Maintained Applications module required by various clients.
- Technologies Used: ASP.Net, SQL Server, Entity Framework, Windows forms, JS, Jquery, Html and CSS.

EDUCATION

06/2017 - 02/2018

Bachelor of Engineering, IT.

Sardar Vallabhbhai Patel Institute of Technology (Vasad).

07/2013 - 05/2017 CGPA 8.02

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

Ticketing Sytem (05/2016 - 03/2017)

 Made ticketing system for raising issues for IT supports as last year project

ACHIEVEMENTS

Held Architecture training for my project at organization level (01/2021)

Cracked Code Vita conducted by TCS and stood in top 1000 rank (12/2015)

LANGUAGES

nglish Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

Gujarati

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

